LAWAL OMOLOLA

Software Engineer

https://github.com/omolola26 https://www.linkedin.com/in/omolola-lawal/ | +2348140802316

PROFILE

A passionate, self-driven and result-oriented software developer in pursuit of opportunities in growing organizations that is willing to offer opportunities for career development, facilitate continuous learning, growth, and create positive impact. Highly energetic and passionate to apply all my skills and professional experiences to achieve organizational goals and also attaining a successful career.

TECHNICAL SKILL

- Develop webpage using HTML5 and CSS3
- Knowledge of programming languages JavaScript
- Proficient with JavaScript framework React and Node.js
- Working experience handling database with SQL
- Proficient use of Version Control Management Git& GitHub
- Efficient knowledge and skills in Word Press

SOFT SKILLS:

- Problem solving skills
- Time Management
- Inter and intrapersonal skills
- Excellent communication skill
- Solution oriented
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Content writing
- Self-learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Fellow

The Bulb Africa, Jibowu Lagos

May2021 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Writing and maintaining code, Learning codebase and improving my coding skills.
- Frequent design meetings and collaborating on project.
- Analyse the structure and design of web pages.

- Assembled web pages with basic component using react.
- Debug website issues that arise.
- Track project using GitHub
- Expand database using MySQL and services with Agile/SCRUM methodology.

Web Designer Trainee

GoMyCode

Jan 2021 – May 2021

Responsibilities:

- Learning and designing responsive websites with HTML/CSS/ JAVASCRIPT/REACT.JS
- Executing instructions from the team lead when building projects
- Researching and implementing designs.

Operations Staff

NIKE STICHIES, Yaba Lagos

Sept 2017 - Dec 2019

Responsibilities:

- Taking inventory and ordering office supplies as needed.
- Executing administrative duties
- Assisting to the creation of brand designs.

EDUCATION

COLLEGE OF EDUCATION NIGERIA

Ijaniki, Badagry road, Lagos 2012 – 2015

Diploma, Linguistics

CORAL BELL COLLEGEWASSCE *1jayi, Lagos*2010 – 2013

TOOLS

Frameworks: Bootstrap, React, Node.js

Version control: Git, GitHub.

Project Management: Trello.

Database: My SQL, Mongo DB.

Programming Language: JavaScript.

API Development Environment: Postman, Insomnia.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Blog Application

A web platform to create a post, edit

, delete and access comments under each

Post.

NodeJS (Express) and React.js

PERSONAL PORTFOLIO

A portfolio website, that describe me

As a software engineer.

Developed with JavaScript HTML, CSS.

E- COMMERCE APP

A business website, that involves

Sales transactions, an online shopping website.

Built with react framework,

INTERESTS

Listening to Music, Fashion, Networking with people and Travelling.

REFEREES

Available on Request